Hello friends, welcome, I
am Prince. Friends, today we are going to talk
about the life insurance sector. The
results of two private sector companies, HDFC Life and ICICI Prudential, have been declared.
You must be well aware that
both these companies have done a lot of
promotion to sell their products.
But friends, we are inverters and
we would like to see their data, their
outlook, which one should we invest in, which one is good and which one is
not.
Ultimately, we have to keep in mind
which stock can give higher returns
and can this be a golden opportunity for 10 years
if we want to invest here. So
friends, let's start.
First of all, let's know what are the
four news in 2020 that is giving a boost to the
Indian life insurance sector.
Friends, this is the first news, friends, first of all, let's
look at the alternative tags which were
introduced in this budget. The second
news is that we will cover it, friends, the
premium hike will happen soon.
Thirdly, friends, we will discuss
LIC's take on this.  The IPO is about to come and we are going to
cover the news about the To Win or
Nation by Blog Godown that has happened. So
friends, first of all let's see
how the Alternate Tax Regime is going to
package our life
insurance. We all know that
in Britain, to save our taxes,
we used to show some kind of investment. There were
many deductions available in LIC or life insurance product channels.
And friends, now because you will
get an option that you
can do sex every day by removing these deductions, then
many people may not invest
much in life insurance products because of this.
But friends,
because life insurance product has become a completely
emotional game, it is not just
about tax saving. In this case,
friends, it is possible that people may
not be much concerned with tax and it may happen that
friends, you have to do retirement
planning for your friends or you have to prepare for your child
or
you want to provide for your family. So,
due to such regency, people  If you are
buying life insurance products, it is
believed that due to lack of tax deduction,
people will stop buying life insurance and all these
things are being ignored a bit,
industry experts say this,
friends, long term in fact, the
alternative route of income tax is going to decrease at this time, anyway, there are many
countries where there is
no deduction in income tax, if
you invest money in any life insurance product, then
people
buy a lot of life insurance policies and make a good investment in
it, second friends, now let's
talk about a hike in green bean
premium, first of all let's understand the prices, there is an
insurance company which
sells you the product, sells you the policy,
after that they get the policies insured
so that their risk is reduced and
for this green bean they have to pay a premium,
now friends, because there has been an
increase in this year, so
in such a question, there is a company called Four Inch Means,
they have increased the premium,
due to which it is possible that your
company may increase the premium or else
It is possible that they
earn profit on the basis of their cost, so in such a case, the
relation premium can be another big issue, it is
possible that in this case
their profit may decrease or their
policy premium may get paid and if its demand
increases due to any thing, then its demand
increases, so in such a case the
company can do negotiations to reduce the cost or else the
entire cost can be passed on to the customer, by the way
friends, the richest
insurance is in the case of
protection plan, vitamins and minerals
etc. Now when you open many premiums, then you might see
some ad of ICICI or
HDFC Life, so in such a case the
expectations of paying its premium increase, so let us
cover the third thing which can
pack up to life insurance, that is LIC's IPO, LIC will have
a very big IPO, a
company bigger than Reliance, it is being considered that
where the government wants to sell its stake,
then it can earn lakhs  It will be worth crores of rupees,
friends, but this LIC IPO is
facing some challenges right now. The biggest challenge is
that the market is moving a bit slow, so
in such a situation, launching an IPO would not be a good idea,
but its validation is
not so easy. It was launched in 2018
that three government insurance companies would be
launched - National Insurance Company,
United Insurance Company, and Oriental
Insurance Company. That has not happened yet. So, through the
LIC IPO,
foreign investors will be
attracted to India. Along with this, we
can see that other companies in the private insurance sector can
also get themselves listed. It is being said to be
very good for all private insurance in the long term. There is
still a
silver lining. Thirty percent have been
bought in Max Insurance. Friends, there is a good
type of life insurance here, which is going to play a
big role in listing space,
etc. In the coming
days, friends, this
thing is being considered positive here.
Now, friends, let's talk about the recent problem with
which all of you are facing. Not a single person in the entire country is facing this problem.  There will
not be a human being who has
not gone through this problem, he is a giver to friends
and because of that the donation has been returned,
because of this life insurance vacancy happened, in
fact many missions have put a speed
breaker on it, friends, but it is believed
that because of this this Kunwar is
not going to change in life insurance,
now let us quickly see
what kind of return both the stocks have given in the share price
within the last one year, so first of all let us see
ICICI Prudential,
friends, right now its price is at Rs.24 and
within the last one year its test has been very
good, that many members like To Win In have
fallen to 70-80 cents, so
in such a case, a good return of 3.94 can be given on Sunday,
this is what I have seen, friends,
from the tip, you can see the link of the tip in the description, you can
see in the pin comment, who is the
sponsor of our video, so please do visit
it once, so secondly let us
talk about HDFC Life, so
look at it also, friends, what has it done in the last one
year  It has given a return of 20% so
far, the stock is of 200% on it,
even in such a falling market, a
very good trend has been seen here, if
friends, we talk about
what kind of returns ICICI Prudential has given in the last one, then
friends, here is the
result, after the result, there has been a
surge here, whereas friends, if we
talk about HDFC Life, then in the
last one, there has been a
negative return here, but again
after diesel, a buying
environment has been seen here again, now friends, we would
like to see how are the internals of the company,
how are its friends, what are
its fundamentals, etc., so
through some pictures,
friends, I have
made a special slide here for you, let's see
200 HDFC Life, here you will
see its market cap, it is 980, if
you look at ICICI Prudential, it is of 55
thousand rupees, let me tell you clearly  Let me tell you
that today's date is 28th April 2017 and the
current market price that we have just seen is
running at 487 for HDFC Life and
you will see that for ICICI Prudential it is
at 383. If you see where they have
invested the money that they have taken from people through policy products,
then you will see that there is an
amount of Rs 1.27 lakh crore for ICICI Life. If
you look at ICICI Prudential, there is Rs
1.5 lakh crore. So you will
see that ICICI Prudential Life has a
better NYU. You will see
friends, ninety six percent of
HDFC Life is under Government Securities. If we
go to Britain and see, it is
98%. And friends, if we look at the proposals in
2019, then the
work of ICICI Life is big. One person or again the problem has
decreased and if we
talk about solvency of countries, then
easily the pressure appears to be stronger than
124.  Its earlier
solvency was 215 percent, whereas HDFC
Life's earlier solvency was 98% in other countries and it has been
practiced at 180 percent. If we
talk about Indian absolute value
here, then friends, the book
value here is not that reliable,
you have read the book on major elements, it is
not considered that reliable, that is why every
insurance company calculates its embedded value, so
friends, if we talk about embedded value here, then the
100 percent road of ICICI Life is 60 percent from last year, if we
talk about ICICI Prudential, then
6.5 percent
growth has been shown here from last year and it has reached Rs
23500 crore, if friends, if
we talk about new special people, then here the
value of any life insurance company is
also 70%, its future value
comes from new insurance business, so a
huge new business comes out, so you will see
friends, here it is 1919 crore.  25% is the
entire offer. Talking about canceling it from I,
it appears to be at Rs 1605 crore. We will
talk a little more about it. Finally,
friends, if we talk about the
returns generated by the enterprises at Aamby Valley Open, then you can see that the
interest rate of HDFC Life is 7.5 per cent
and that of ICICI Prudential is
15.2 per cent. Because of this, it
is at a premium and it is getting more elevations in the market.
Friends, if we
talk about price book value, then
here we will talk about price embedded
value. Here, ICICI Life is getting an
elevation of 0.7 times
and ICICI Prudential is getting an
elevation of 2.5 times. In this case,
you will get comfortable validations
in ICICI Prudential. And friends, if we
talk about P, ​​here
in HDFC Life, it is 73rd PIN and you must have
understood the stop on A potential text.
So ICICI Prudential can be
there but if you look at the operating details
on embedded value then
ICICI Prudential has 15%
but if you look at HDFC Life then it is 22%.
If friends, if you look at the quality then you will
see a little less quality in HDFC Life but friends, if you
talk about ICICI, then there is a more risky effect,
here you will see high quality there.
Now friends, let us talk about the recent
results, so friends, let us first look at the quarterly form and
talk about the premium income,
so if I
look at ICICI Life, then its premium has increased by
2.1% in these quarters,
it has reached 10764 crores. If we talk about ICICI Prudential, then it has
increased by 4.17% and reached 10600 75
crores. So if we talk about its investment, then I
told you that the market was
going negative and due to this
their investment is weak - it has gone up, so if we
look at the cost, then friends, it is of
added
type.  - It has gone up to Rs 10,000 crore
and friends, you can see that in the
last quarter, that is, within the Flu f-18,
375 products - if we talk about the loss, then
it is a bit high, you can see
friends, Kota four has 80 crores, whereas
in the Cotton for f-18 center, 560 abortions, the
investment corporation A zone loss is
shown here, so the loss of such lives is comfortably less,
you will see it around 3800 and if you
see in cancelling it, then it will
appear four times more than this, friends, approximately Rs 12117 crore,
so you can understand friends, this
is a very big launch,
ICICI Prudential has shown it as an investment loss and
you will see the consequences of this in its share
price also, if friends, people
talk about its heat, then the
loss of such lives has increased by one percent, it has said that
1295 crores paper, if we talk about ICICI Prudential, then
their loss
is double on six, 1069 producers are
associated with the insurance sector.  Let's talk about some of these things
like the Valley of the New Branch Office
gives seventy percent value, gives 70%
validation
in life insurance, so if you see the growth of ICICI Prudential
there, you will see a bar like this, it
is five percent, if you
see their margin, in the value of the jobs,
you can see that ICICI
Prudential has 21.7 but HDFC Life has
25.9 versus annual premium
equivalent, you will see friends, here
two things are considered, one is
protection plan and the other is unit
linked friend, so friends, here you will
see that there is
always high margin in protection plan and all types of
companies are engaged in selling protection plans,
like vitamin schedule plane crash, I am
talking about the same thing, so here the
growth of ICICI Prudential is 55 percent,
ICICI has established a
very good market in selling its term insurance,
so HDFC Life has a little profit of
22%, it is an ICC company.  It is less in the
unit linked plan but still it does not reduce by 200%. Now if we see
that by cancelling it, we have
reduced our dependence, then
you will see a negative role of 5.4 per cent there and if we
talk about AC, then
you will see an increase in the ATM point, so if you look at all the
parameters, you will
see AC good, if you look at it, now you will
see this point also, if you look at the profit of the last several years,
you will see it
increasing, but in this Keshavdas
addition, you will see it increasing for some time,
then you will see it coming down also,
friends, in the scanner of AC, ICICI
Prudential is a little more, so I had given you a
price club before this, on
its basis you can know and understand it
well, then which
stock is its and which is not its,
if friends, if I have to invest here, then
I definitely used to do it in the spy scandal, so
if I had 1 lakh rupees, then I used to invest 50 thousand
rupees penniless, so from that  I
got this in 20th ICICI Life
and I have deposited Rs. 25000 in such live scanner
and after that if the market goes
down, I deposit Rs. 3510 in it, then
I used to deposit my second installment of Rs. 25281 here.
You must have liked this video a lot,
if you liked it then like it and
share it and friends, if you have
not subscribed to our channel then
subscribe today. Thank you friends, we will make more such
videos together, till then
hello.